Guide to the Affirmative Action Office Records 1971-2010
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center
Affirmative Action Office Records
1971-2010
1985-2000
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center Special Collections & University Archives Research Center 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2165 Email: archives@oregonstate.edu Web: http://archives.library.oregonstate.edu
RG 172
Oregon State University. Office of Affirmative Action and Equal Opportunity.
9.2 cubic feet, including 5 photographs 10 boxes
The Affirmative Action Office Records document the development and implementation of affirmative action and equal employment opportunity programs at Oregon State University, especially with regard to women, ethnic minorities, individuals with disabilities, and veterans. The records include subject files, affirmative action plans, policies and procedures, reports, and publications. The Office of Affirmative Action and Equal Opportunity was established at Oregon State University in 1972.
Historical Note:
Oregon State University's Office of Affirmative Action and Equal Opportunity (OAAEO) was founded in 1972 to ensure that all University community members uphold federal and state civil rights laws and regulations as well as the University's equal opportunity policies.
The OAAEO manages the University's affirmative action and equal opportunity efforts by establishing policies and procedures and by evaluating hiring and recruitment practices. The office investigates and resolves discrimination complaints and coordinates the University's obligations under the Americans with Disabilities Act. The OAAEO also offers training and education on a variety of topics related to affirmative action and equal opportunity.
Directors of the Office of Affirmative Action and Equal Opportunity have included Ronald McClain (1973-1975); Pearl Spears Gray (1976-1987); Stephanie Sanford (1987-2000); and Angelo Gomez (2000-).
The Affirmative Action Office Records document the development and implementation of affirmative action and equal employment opportunity policies, plans, and programs at Oregon State University, especially with regard to women, ethnic minorities, individuals with disabilities, and veterans. The records include correspondence, handbooks, meeting minutes, newspaper clippings, notes, overhead transparencies, photographs, policies and procedures, publications, reports, speeches, and survey records.
The collection includes substantive materials pertaining to athletics compliance, civil rights, domestic partner policies, gender equity, grievance procedures, harassment, racism, recruitment and retention of minority students, sexism, and sexual orientation. The records document the development of minority action plans for campus units; interactions with state and regional advocacy groups; university committees, such as the President's Commission on the Status of Women, Minority Affairs Commission, and Board of Visitors for Minority Affairs; collection of summary data on faculty, staff, and students at Oregon State; and presentations and training workshops.
Most of the materials in this collection reflect Stephanie Sanford's tenure as Director of the OAAEO in 1987-2000. Beyond the correspondence, reports, and policies generated by Sanford, the collection includes several speeches she gave as well as her published articles.
The collection includes 5 photographic prints of Affirmative Action staff at a staff retreat in 1996.
Collection is open for research. Access to materials in Series I pertaining to the U.S. Department of Education Office of Civil Rights (OCR) compliance review of athletics is restricted and subject to review by the University Archivist.
The Affirmative Action Office Records are arranged in 5 series: I. Subject Files, 1971-2009; Affirmative Action Plans, 1971-1991; III. Policies and Procedures, 1981-1999; IV. Reports, 1976-1998; and V. Publications, 1977-2010.
The records were transferred to the University Archives in numerous accessions from 1991 through 2010; the bulk of the records were transferred in 2007.
Additions to the collection are expected.
The Affirmative Action Office Records are a component of the Oregon Multicultural Archives. Additional materials pertaining to affirmative action at Oregon State University are available in the records of the President's Office (RG 013), President's Commission on the Status of Women (RG 159), Women's Center (RG 243), Associated Students of OSU (RG 011), and Office of Multicultural Affairs (RG 225) as well as the Memorabilia Collection. The records of many colleges, academic departments, and administrative offices include affirmative action plans for those units.
Sanford, Stephanie.; Gray, Pearl Spears.
Oregon State University. President's Commission on the Status of Women.; Oregon State University--Administration.; Oregon State University--Faculty.; Oregon State University--Sports.; Oregon State University--Students.
Affirmative action programs--Oregon--Corvallis--Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Affirmative action programs in education--Oregon--Corvallis.; Diversity in the workplace--Oregon--Corvallis.; Domestic partner benefits--Oregon--Corvallis.; Faculty integration--Oregon--Corvallis.; Gay college students--Oregon--Corvallis.; Minorities--Employment--Oregon.; Minority college students--Oregon.; Minority college teachers--Oregon--Corvallis.; People with disabilities--Employment--Oregon--Corvallis.; Sex discrimination in sports--Oregon--Corvallis.; Sexual harassment in universities and colleges--Oregon--Corvallis.; Sports for women--Oregon--Corvallis.;; Women--Education (Higher)--Oregon--Corvallis.; Women athletes--Oregon--Corvallis.
Photographic prints.
African Americans; Civil Rights; Colleges and Universities; Gays and Lesbians; Latinos and Latinas; Native Americans; Sports and Recreation; Women; Oregon; Corvallis; Electronic Records; Photographs
- Subject Files, 1971-2009; Series I
  Series I comprises the bulk of the collection and documents the functioning and programs of the Affirmative Action Office at Oregon State University. The subject files include correspondence, reference materials, presentations, speeches, meeting minutes and committee records, and newspaper clippings. The records document affirmative action in employment of women, minorities, individuals with disabilities, and veterans as well as civil rights, harassment, sexism, recruitment and retention of minority students, domestic partner policies, grievance procedures, and athletics compliance.
  - Academic Council meeting minutes, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - Accreditation, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Administrative Response Team, 1992-1994 (Box 1)
  - Affirmative Action and Equal Opportunity Overheads for Presentations, 1994-1999 (Box 1)
  - Affirmative Action Clippings, 1989-2003 (Box 1)
  - Affirmative Action Debate, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Affirmative Action Goals and Objectives, 1986-1996 (Box 1)
  - Affirmative Action Office brochure, 1999 (Box 1)
    Includes 3 zip disks.
  - Affirmative Action Review, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Affirmative Action Ways and Means Report, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Affirmative Action Various, 1999-2000
    - Legal developments related to Affirmative Action, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Federal Register - New Affirmative Action Changes, 2000 (Box 1)
  - African Students Association, 1999 (Box 1)
  - After 8, 1991-1994 (Box 1)
    Corvallis gay and lesbian group.
  - Americans with Disabilities Act, 1989-1999
    - General Files, 1989-1993; 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Americans with Disabilities Act software floppy disk, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Technical Assistance Program, 1991-1999 (Box 1)
    - Americans with Disabilities Act Transition Plan, 1992; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Announcements, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Announcements, 2009 (Box 1)
  - Asian and Pacific Islanders, 1986-1999 (Box 1)
  - Athletics, 1988-1996 (Box 1)
    - NCAA Gender Equity Survey, 1992-1996 (Box 1)
    - Salaries, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - Availability/Employment Department, 2002-2004 (Box 1)
    State of Oregon statistics.
  - Award records - OSU Outstanding Service Award to Persons with Disabilities, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Bakke Decision, 1978 (Box 1)
    Implications for law and race.
  - Benton County Affirmative Action Plan, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Bias-Free Language Guide, 1993 (Box 1)
    Includes one floppy disk.
  - Board of Visitors for Minority Affairs, 1986-1998
    - History, 1986-1997 (Box 1)
    - Membership lists, 1987-1998 (Box 1)
    - Working Together for the Future report, 1987-1991 (Box 1)
  - Boycott, 1996 (Box 1)
    Student protest at OSU regarding racism.
  - Buckley Amendment, 1990-1999 (Box 1)
    Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
  - Budgets and Planning - Assessment of Campus Information Needs report, 1995-1999 (Box 1)
  - Campus Security Act, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Center for Individual Rights - The Rights of College Students handbook, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Center for Women policy studies, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Civil Rights Act, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Compliance Review - Education and Welfare & Office for Civil Rights contract, 1975-1978 (Box 2)
  - Conferences, 1991-2000
    - Beyond Affirmative Action: Maintaining Campus Diversity, 1998 (Box 2)
    - Environmental Engineering, 1991 (Box 2)
      Speech by Stephanie Sanford for meeting.
    - Oregon Minority Summit 2000, 1997-2000 (Box 2)
    - University of Oregon Education 2000, 1999 (Box 2)
      Students of color.
  - Contractor policies, 1997-2003 (Box 2)
  - Commission on Racism, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
  - Cooperative Agreements, 1980-1993 (Box 2)
  - Core Curriculum meetings, 1996-2001 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and procedures, 1972-1975 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Corvallis, 1989-1998
    - General, 1989-1998 (Box 2)
    - Police Department, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
    - Corvallis Gazette-Times, 1996-1997 (Box 2)
  - CSSA practicum, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Difference, Power, and Discrimination (DPD) program, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - Directories, 1998-2005
    - Faculty of Color Resource Directory, 2005 (Box 2)
    - OSU Directory of Alternative Formats, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Disability, 1988-1998
    - Hiring Goals, Classified/Management, 1988-1991 (Box 2)
    - Learning, 1985-1991 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1988-1991 (Box 2)
    - Philosophy, 1988-1998 (Box 2)
    - Survey for OSU Employees with Disabilities, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Advisory Board for HIRE (Hiring Individuals Ready for Employment), 1999 (Box 2)
  - Diversity Plan, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Domestic Partners, 1989-2000
    - Benefits, 1995-2000 (Box 2)
    - Issues, 1994-1996 (Box 2)
    - Policy, 1989-1999 (Box 2)
  - Enrollment and Management Services, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - Executive Order - Employment of Persons with Disabilities, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Faculty, 1981-1999
    - Faculty Senate, 1997-1999 (Box 3)
    - Grievance procedures, 1989 (Box 3)
    - Salaries, 1981-1996 (Box 3)
    - Women, 1986-1997 (Box 3)
  - Fair Labor Standards Association, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Family Acts and Programs, 1989-2000
    - Family Educational Privacy Rights Act (FERPA), 2000 (Box 3)
    - Family Employment Program, 1989-1994 (Box 3)
    - Family and Medical Leave Act, 1993-1995 (Box 3)
  - Forestry at Risk program, 1988-1990 (Box 3)
  - Graduate School, 1984-2002
    - Graduate recruitment and retention, 1984-1989 (Box 3)
    - Graduate school, 1988-1999 (Box 3)
    - Graduate school registration, 1999-2002 (Box 3)
    - Graduate school statistics, 1988-2000 (Box 3)
  - Graduation Summary Reports, 1988-2000 (Box 3)
  - Graphic Identity guide, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Grievance Procedures
    - General, 1973-1987 (Box 3)
    - Drafting Commission, 1983-1988 (Box 3)
  - Guidelines for Bias-Free Publishing, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Harassment
    - Computer harassment, 1996 (Box 3)
    - Statutes, 1989 (Box 3)
    - Discrimination Grievance Procedures brochure, undated (Box 3)
    - Peer harassment, 1988 (Box 3)
    - Administrative Response Team - Procedures for Responding to Incidents of Harassment and Discrimination, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Hate crimes, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Hawkins Bill, 1989 (Box 3)
    HR 2235 - Workforce 2000 Employment Readiness Act of 1989
  - Health Careers Opportunity Program (HCOP), 1988 (Box 3)
  - Hewlett-Packard Corporation, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Higher Education Efficiency Acts 1 & 2, 1990-1997 (Box 3)
  - Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) assessment, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Hispanics -- Conditions of, 1985-1987 (Box 3)
  - Hispanics -- Association of College and Universities, 1987-1994 (Box 3)
  - History of Women at OSU, 1971-1990 (Box 3)
  - Human Resources Department
    - General, 1988-1995 (Box 3)
    - Consolidation, 1998; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Human Resources Information System database development, 1991-1998; 3 folders (Box 3-4)
    - HRIC database, 1998; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Training, 1992-1999 (Box 4)
  - Immigration Reform and Control Act, 1987-1994 (Box 4)
  - Inter-fraternity Council, 1990-1996 (Box 4)
  - International Education, 1987-1999 (Box 4)
  - Integrated Postsecondary Education Data System (IPEDS) faculty and staff surveys, 1973-2003 (Box 4)
    3 folders
  - King, Martin Luther, celebrations, 1999-2000 (Box 4)
  - Leadership, 2000 (Box 4)
    Retreat.
  - Legal Advisor, 1992-1998 (Box 4)
  - Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual Association, 1987-1995 (Box 4)
  - Management Service Transition, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Mediation - Community services, 1993-1999 (Box 4)
  - Mentoring, 1988-1998 (Box 4)
  - Minority Action Program, 1989-1996
    - Engineering, 1989-1996 (Box 4)
    - Forestry, 1989-1994 (Box 4)
    - General, 1989-1991 (Box 4)
    - Health and Human Performance, 1990-1996 (Box 4)
    - Home Economics, 1990-1994 (Box 4)
    - Liberal Arts, 1989-1994 (Box 4)
    - Business, 1989-1994 (Box 4)
    - Components, 1989 (Box 4)
    - Education, 1989-1990 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1990 (Box 4)
    - Oceanography, 1989-1997 (Box 4)
    - Pharmacy, 1989-1996 (Box 4)
    - Science, 1989-1996 (Box 4)
    - Status reports, 1991 (Box 4)
    - Veterinary medicine, 1989-1991 (Box 4)
  - Minority Affairs Commission, 1989-1995 (Box 5)
  - Minority Students, 1995-1997
    - Boycott, 1995-1997 (Box 5)
    - Ethnic Minorities and the OSU Greek System report, undated (Box 5)
      Perhaps 1980s.
  - Miscellaneous Statistics and Information, 1987-2000 (Box 5)
  - Multicultural Affairs Office, 1990-2000 (Box 5)
  - National Association of Women in Education, 1999-2000 (Box 5)
  - National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) Gender Equity Study, 1997 (Box 5)
  - National Institute of Dispute Resolution, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Native Americans, 1989-1995 (Box 5)
  - Northwest Equal Employment Seminar, 1999 (Box 5)
  - Northwest Coalition Against Malicious Harassment, 1991-1992 (Box 5)
  - Northwest Equal Employment Opportunity (NWEEO)/Affirmative Action Association, 1999 (Box 5)
  - Odyssey Program, 1998-2000 (Box 5)
  - Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs (OFCCP) review, 1985-2000 (Box 5)
    2 folders
  - Ombudsperson, 1987-1994 (Box 5)
  - Oregon Organizations, 1991-1999
    - Oregon Assembly for Black Affairs, 1993-1995 (Box 5)
    - Oregon Bureau of Labor Civil Rights Division, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Oregon Citizens Alliance, 1991-1992 (Box 5)
    - Oregon Commission on Black Affairs, 1991-1994 (Box 5)
    - Oregon Commission on Disabilities, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Oregon Commission on Racism report, 1991-1992 (Box 5)
    - Oregon Council for Hispanic Advancement, 1992 (Box 5)
    - Oregon Progress Board, 1999 (Box 5)
    - Oregon State Bar, 1997 (Box 5)
  - OSU Conciliation Agreement, 1978-1982 (Box 5)
  - Oregon University System, 1995-1997 (Box 5)
  - Oregonian newspaper, 1988-1995 (Box 5)
  - Pacific-10 Athletic Conference, 1997-2000 (Box 5)
  - Parking study, 2003-2005 (Box 5)
  - Performance funding, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Presentations, 1993-1995 (Box 6)
    Speeches given by Stephanie Sanford.
  - President's Commission on Hate Related Activities (PCHRA), 1993-1997; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - President's Commission on the Status of Women (PCOSW), 1987-2000
    - General, 1987-2000; 6 folders (Box 6)
      Includes meeting minutes, reports, and data.
    - Graduate Assistantships, 1988-1995 (Box 6)
    - Achieving Parity for Women at OSU, 1999 (Box 6)
    - Women's Lives, Women's Voices, Women's Solutions: Shaping a National Agenda for Women in Higher Education caucus, 2000 (Box 6)
    - Flyer mock-ups and drafts, circa 1993 (Box 6)
    - Subcommittees, 1995-1996 (Box 6)
  - Press, 1972-1992 (Box 6)
    Primarily clippings related to affirmative action.
  - PROMISE internship program, 1993-2001; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Promotion and tenure, 1983-2003
    - Summary reports, 1983-2003 (Box 7)
    - Guidelines, 1988-2001 (Box 7)
  - Proposal to Confront Campus-Wide Discrimination, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Provost's (Academic) Council, 1999-2000 (Box 7)
  - Public Records Disclosure Order petition, 1996 (Box 7)
  - Race and Ethnicity, 1973-2000
    - Racial/ethnic codes, 1988-1998 (Box 7)
    - Racial Equality brochure, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Racism language, 1973-1985 (Box 7)
    - Asian/Pacific American Education Office Annual Report, 2000 (Box 7)
    - Ford Foundation Fellowships for Minorities (Box 7)
    - Hispanic Outlook, 1999 (Box 7)
    - Improving the Racial Climate at OSU report, 1999 (Box 7)
    - Minorities in Higher Education status reports, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Working Together for the Future: Towards Racial and Cultural Diversity at OSU, 1987 (Box 7)
      OSU Board of Visitors for Minority Affairs plan.
    - Students of Color Recruitment and Retention Committee, 1999 (Box 7)
  - Reference materials on sexual harassment, 1980-1993; 3 folders (Box 7)
    Policies, laws, and case studies.
  - Saferide shuttle service, 1987-1988 (Box 7)
  - Safe Zones: Resource Guide, Summer, 1993 (Box 7)
    Resources for the gay, lesbian, and bisexual community in Corvallis.
  - Stephanie Sanford and Donna Eder's published articles, 1984-1986 (Box 7)
  - Sexism, 1984-1999
    - General, 1984-1993 (Box 7)
    - Sexism and language, 1989-1999 (Box 7)
  - Sexual assault support services, 1994-1997 (Box 7)
  - Sexual orientation, 1981-1999
    - Films, 1993 (Box 7)
    - Gays in the military, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
    - Gay and Lesbian Advocates and Defenders (GLAD), 1992 (Box 7)
    - General, 1993-1999 (Box 7)
    - Homophobia, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Oregon Citizens Alliance petition, 1991 (Box 7)
    - Portland city policies, 1992 (Box 7)
    - ROTC, 1990-1995 (Box 7)
    - Training, 1981-1992 (Box 7)
  - Speakers, 1988-1994 (Box 7)
  - Staff retreats, 1986-2002 (Box 7)
    Includes 5 photographs of Affirmative Action staff at a staff retreat in 1996.
  - State of Oregon, 1979-1996 (Box 7)
  - Student Affairs Administrative Response Team (STAART), 1998-1999 (Box 7)
  - Student funding requests for association events, 1994-1995 (Box 7)
  - Task Forces, 1986-1999
    - Benton County Ethnic Diversity, 1992-1994 (Box 7)
    - Minority issues at OSU, 1986 (Box 7)
    - Together Everyone Accomplishes More (TEAM), 1999 (Box 7)
  - Title IX overhead transparencies (Box 7)
  - Total Quality Management, 1991-1996 (Box 7)
  - Training, 1985-1999
    - Beyond Black and White, 1999 (Box 8)
      PBS television program.
    - Hiring procedures, 1989 (Box 8)
    - Interviewing, 1986 (Box 8)
    - More than a Gut Feeling: Training Leader's Guide, circa 1985 (Box 8)
    - Printing and Mailing, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Sexual harassment, 1986-1996 (Box 8)
  - Trial transcripts and legal records, 1984; 2 folders (Box 8)
    Class action lawsuit of Anna Peck vs. the Oregon State System of Higher Education.
  - Understanding the Employer's New USERRA Obligations, undated (Box 8)
  - University Advisory Committee for Persons with Disabilities, 1986-2004; 7 folders (Box 8)
  - University of Oregon Affirmative Action Office, 1989-1995 (Box 8)
  - University Process Review - Implementation Plan and Schedule, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - Visiting-Artist-in-Residence program, 1987-1988 (Box 8)
  - Warm Springs Reservation, 1994-1995 (Box 8)
  - Women's Center Advisory Committee, 1996-2001 (Box 8)
  - Women, 1986-2000
    - Women's Lives - teleconference presentation, 2000 (Box 8)
    - Office of Women in International Development (OSU), 1986-1989 (Box 8)
    - General, 1986-1999 (Box 8)
  - Athletics Compliance Review, 1991; 3 folders (Box 10)
    Access restricted and subject to review by the University Archivist.
    Information about athletics operations compiled for an U.S. Department of Education Office of Civil Rights (OCR) compliance review.
- Affirmative Action Plans, 1971-1991; Series II
  Series II consists of Oregon State University Affirmative Action plans and guidelines issued in 1971, 1975, 1977, 1989, and 1991. The plans include OSU's Affirmative Action Policy Statement as well as information regarding the administrative organization and responsibility for implementation of the plan; employment programs; student affirmative action programs; dissemination of the policy and plan; monitoring, evaluation, and reporting; and affirmative action programs for veterans and persons with disabilities.
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Affirmative Action Compliance Program, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Affirmative Action Plan, December 1975 (Box 8)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity and Affirmative Action Guidelines, 1977 (Box 8)
  - Affirmative Action Plan for 1989/91 Biennium (Box 8)
  - Affirmative Action Plan for 1991/1993 Biennium (Box 8)
- Policies and Procedures, 1981-1999; Series III
  Series III consists of affirmative action and other policies and procedures specific to Oregon State University. These include the Affirmative Action Policies and Procedures Handbook, distributed as part of OSU's Administrative Policy and Procedures Manual, as well as policies regarding AIDS, domestic partners, English language proficiency, family support, free speech, non-discrimination on the basis of disability, religion, and sexual harrassment.
  - Affirmative Action Policies and Procedures Handbook, 1981-1994; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Policy Against Discriminatory Harassment, 1991 (Box 9)
  - Academic appointments, 1986-1987 (Box 9)
  - Acceptable use, 1996-1998 (Box 9)
  - Affirmative action and equal opportunity, September, 1996 (Box 9)
  - AIDS, 1989 (Box 9)
  - Alcoholic beverages, 1988 (Box 9)
  - Bomb threats, 1991 (Box 9)
  - Disaster Management Plan, 1991-1997 (Box 9)
  - Domestic partners, 1992-1999; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Duplication of materials, 1991 (Box 9)
  - English language proficiency, 1991 (Box 9)
  - Family support, 1996-1999 (Box 9)
  - Free speech, 1989 (Box 9)
  - Graphic identity, 1997 (Box 9)
  - Human resources, 1989-1998 (Box 9)
  - Policy and Guidelines for Nondiscrimination on the Basis of Disability, 1991 (Box 9)
  - Political activity guidelines, 1989-1993 (Box 9)
  - Protocol for international visitors, 1989-1993 (Box 9)
  - Prejudice, 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - Religion, 1997 (Box 9)
  - Sexual Harassment Policy, 1994-1996; 2 folders (Box 9)
- Reports, 1976-1998; Series IV
  Series IV consists of reports prepared or received by the Affirmative Action office and includes the Affirmative Action Annual Report for 1986-1987 and OSU's Title IX Interim Report completed in 1976. This report includes detailed analysis and review of the policies and procedures of colleges, departments, and other units regarding women. This review specifically addressed financial aid, scholarships, and publications. It does not include information on intercollegiate athletics, intramurals, or recreational sports. Of special note is the 1994 report on minority faculty recruitment and the perceptions of the campus climate by minority faculty, which is available online.
  - Affirmative Action Annual Report for 1986/87, 1987 (Box 9)
  - Higher Education Staff Information (EEO-6) report for 1991 (Box 9)